

# Atulya Saraswat

+918619473517

saraswat541@gmail.com

Kota, India 324005

# SKILLS

- Node Is
- Express Is
- MongoDb
- Laravel
- MySQL
- Swagger API
- Flutter
- JavaScript

## LANGUAGES

### English

Advanced (C1)

#### Hindi

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Adaptable Senior Software Engineer talented at providing customized and optimized solutions for all needs. Thrives within tight deadlines by applying agile development strategies. Comfortable overseeing large-scale development teams or independently coding complex projects. Persistent professional equipped with 4+ years of comprehensive experience in Service and product based industry. Provides strong technical direction across multiple projects. Responsible and articulate individual with strengths in solutions optimization, mobile and cloud solutions and global project management.

## **WORK HISTORY**

May 2023 - Current

Senior Software Engineer, Sutherland Global Pvt Ltd, Hyderabd

- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues.
- · Worked with development teams to correct problems and run test scenarios.
- Promoted technical leadership to entry-level and junior engineers in complex enterprise system environment.
- Led software development initiative as subject matter expert and primary point-ofcontact for project management staff.

November 2021 - April 2023

Senior Software Engineer, Ongraph Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Jaipur

- Wrote highly maintainable, solid code for software system, forming core framework and earning consistent praise from subsequent developers since initial version
- Communicated technical development stages and provided design support to businesses and other stakeholders encouraging participation for on-time execution
- Lead of team of developers also and manage their productivity as well along with my work

August 2015 - May 2019

Software Developer, SVM Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Hyderabad

- Introduced agile methodologies and development best practices to division to enhance product development
- Developed software for both desktop and mobile operating systems
- Coordinated with project management staff on database development timelines and project scope
- Assisted in business acquisition efforts by designing customized solutions for proposals to potential customers
- Implemented target tracking to research prototypes over large data sets
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.

# **EDUCATION**

B.Tech

Global Institute Of Technology, Jaipur

MR

Sumit Bal Sr. Sec. School, International School, Kota